STEPHEN NEIL BUSKIE

BUSINESS ANALYST | ENGINEER

947 Waverly Street, Houston, Texas, 77008

stephenbuskie2@hotmail.com | https://sbuskie.github.io/# | +44 7979532368 | +1 832 616 7767

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am inquisitive by nature. This led me to engineering where I sought to improve the world through applied sciences. I once believed optimising production from oil and gas assets achieved this. I was wrong. I need to apply my world class engineering skillset to make tangible positive changes to the world that I can be proud of.

I have a proven track record of exceptional communication skills for technical and non-technical information. This includes experience influencing joint-ventures on billion dollar investments and c-suite executive reporting. Additionally demonstrated the ability to work effectively with multiple cultures through respect and communication while coordinating globally deployed teams for business planning purposes.

Known for focused and consistent business delivery supported by the highest quality technical analysis. My experience in building globally deployed digital solutions has taught me the power of big data. I relish working with a company that values big data and advanced analytics and applies them to deliver business results.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Production Performance Squad Lead, bp; Houston, Texas - Jan 2021 - Present

Squad lead for the production performance team, responsible for bp's external reporting of their global hydrocarbon production. This includes managing a multi-disciplinary team of 6 performance analysts and advisors in support of these demands. Accountabilities include owner of production insights into bp's quarterly results announcements, stock exchange announcements, annual report and sustainability report.

Additionally responsible for performance management and coordination of bp's business planning for the production domain. This includes executive reporting and performance management on a weekly, monthly and quarterly basis and liaising with teams across all geographies where bp operate. Lead for production management information during Group Performance Reviews, Operational Performance Reviews and Executive Monthly Production Reviews.

Performance Analyst, bp; Houston, Texas - 2019 -2021

Performance analyst responsible for the integrity, accuracy and timely delivery of management information related to bp's global Upstream hydrocarbon production (>2,500mboed).

Highlights include development lead for digital business intelligence tools related to bp's production portfolio, working with support from bp's data visualisation team. This accountability covered Microsoft Power BI report development and deployment to global users to aid business planning, quarterly variance commentary and executive weekly reporting.

Production subject matter export aligning bp's production management workflows with the reinvented ambition to be net zero by 2050 or sooner, working with the Strategy and Sustainability team. Lead the development of carbon as a production stream with equivalent importance of oil and gas production to facilitate improved carbon forecasting globally. Worked with Palantir Technologies and bp data architects to connect SAP reported hydrocarbon production to the data lake, improving flow of carbon forecasts to executive dashboards, quarterly external reports and bp's annual sustainability report.

Single point of accountability for bp's quarterly production reporting to the market. Including drafting production commentary for stock exchange announcements, leading investor relation supplemental information for quarterly

CFO and CEO investor calls; a team member of the 'panel of experts' providing real-time support to the executives during investor calls. Additional c-suite responsibilities included risk management and reporting coordinator for bp's Reservoir Development (subsurface) function and supporting bp's quarterly appraisal table, part of bp's ~\$12-16bn/ year capital allocation process. Both processes were owned by and delivered to the Upstream COO.

Reservoir Engineer, bp; Aberdeen, UK - 2013-2019

Highly experienced in managing complex reservoirs using both state of the art engineering practices (big data analytics, ensemble modelling and simulation modelling) and analytically from first principles. Demonstrated track record of applying pragmatic engineering practices to solve complex, multi-disciplinary problems. Experienced in all aspects of reservoir and petroleum engineering.

Highlights include:

- Led the successful assessment and approval of a 10-year facility life extension of a giant North Sea oil field. Previous teams had unsuccessfully attempted to gain partner alignment for this project. I identified the triggers behind the misalignment within the joint venture and led the project to resolve the issues. This added >80mmstb gross reserves and >\$350m NPV10 to the joint venture business in the reference case.
- Led North Sea West of Shetland basin future gas strategy for the Area General Manager. This supported bp's aim to be net zero on a Scope 1 and 2 GHG emissions basis. The remit was to assess the technical feasibility for power options for a future offshore fixed platform facility; gas from the basin using the existing gas export infrastructure or leveraging a future onshore 440MW, 103 turbine greenfield wind power development.
- Supported product development for by's relationship with Palantir Technologies, working cross-functionally with Palantir engineers and technology architects to develop world class digital toolkits knitting together real-time sensor data, sparse data sets and simulation forecasts outputs to improve production operations.

EDUCATION

MSc Petroleum Engineering, Distinction; Imperial College London 2012-2013 Graduated with distinction. Attained full corporate sponsorship covering academic fees and living stipend. Attained World Education Service (WES) degree equivalency for USA and Canada.

BEng (Hons) Mechanical Engineering, First Class; The University of Strathclyde 2008-2012 Runner-up of the European Science, Engineering and Technology (SET) awards, in the 'Best Mechanical Engineering Student' category as judged by the Institute of Mechanical Engineers. The SET Awards provide a showcase for educational excellence by publicly recognising the exceptional achievements of both students and universities. They are Europe's most high profile event for science, engineering and technology undergraduates.

Awarded the University of Strathclyde Institute of Mechanical Engineers individual project prize. Additionally awarded final year scholarship based on demonstrated academic record.

SKILLS

Agile Methodologies | Scrum | Management Information | Business Intelligence | Data Analytics | Data Visualisation | Carbon Forecasting | Stock Exchange Announcements | Quarterly Reporting | Investor Relations | Executive Reporting | Finance | Audit | Big Data | Reservoir Engineering | Risk Management | Decision Analysis | Team Leadership | Delivering Under Pressure

TOOLS OF THE TRADE

Microsoft Power BI | Microsoft O365 | Microsoft PowerApps | Azure Dev Ops | Spotfire | SAP | Python | Git | Streamlit